Even saints have a past.
There Be Dragons is a war, history, drama film directed by Roland Joffé.
Arising out of the horror of the Spanish Civil War, a candidate for canonization is investigated by a journalist who discovers his own estranged father had a deep, dark and devastating connection to the saint's life.While researching the life
of Josemaria Escriva, the controversial founder of Opus Dei, the young journalist Robert uncovers hidden stories of his estranged father Manolo, and is taken on a journey through the dark, terrible secrets of his family’s past.
Josemaría, played by Charlie Cox.
Robert, played by Dougray Scott.
Manolo, played by Wes Bentley.
Ildiko, played by Olga Kurylenko.
Oriol, played by Rodrigo Santoro.
Leila, played by Golshifteh Farahani.
There Be Dragons is a 2011 historical epic war drama
film written and directed by Roland Joffé.
Set during the Spanish Civil War of the 1930s, it features themes such as betrayal, love
and hatred, forgiveness, friendship, and finding meaning in everyday life.
It includes the story of soldiers, a journalist, his father, and a real-life priest, Josemaría
Escrivá, the founder of Opus Dei, who was canonized as a Roman Catholic saint.
The film explores themes of spanish civil war (1936-39),
based on true story, priest, catholic, dying.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.